AFRASIYAB (AFROKK) KHAN

hi@afrokk.dev | LinkedIn.com/in/afrasiyab-k | GitHub.com/Afrokk | www.afrokk.dev

SUMMARY

Software Engineering grad with 7 years of experience in the tech industry, **managing** a **1.7M subs YT channel**, **former founder of a tech news website**, and an avid **freelancer** with **works featured** in **Forbes**, **Uber**, and **more**.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: C, Java, Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, SQL (Postgres), HTML/CSS, SASS **Frameworks**: React, Node.js, Flask, Vue.js, Next.js, Nuxt, Express, Bootstrap, Tailwind

Tools: Git, Docker, Jira, REST APIs, CI/CD, Adobe Suite, Figma

EXPERIENCE

Creative Design Manager

March 2019 - Present

YouTube (@xeetechcare)

Remote

- Directed a thriving **1.7 million subscribers** YouTube channel to produce **tech** content for a worldwide audience.
- Managed partnerships with renowned brands including Samsung, Google, Chevrolet, and more across diverse sectors.
 Produced a content library of over 2,000 videos showcasing the latest in technology, spanning smartphones,
- Implemented **SEO strategies** to elevate channel visibility resulting in up to **40% increase in views** from high CPM regions.

Lead Teaching Assistant

January 2022 - December 2022

uWindsor School of Computer Science

Windsor, ON

- Mentored 100s of students in four major Computer Science courses including C, OOP with Java and OS Programming.
- Conducted **workshops** with over **200** students to teach Computer Science tools, including **C**, **Java**, **SQL**, along with **multithreading**, and **network socket** concepts.

Co-founder May 2016 - February 2019

GeeksULTD

Malaysia

• Established and piloted GeeksULTD.COM, a technology/gaming-based website for 3 years.

computers, and electric vehicles, garnering an impressive 5 million monthly views.

- Accelerated website load times by optimizing JavaScript & CSS files and integrating CDN technologies resulting in up to 2x faster load times.
- Published over 550 articles and reviews related to computers, technology, and gaming, for over 100K monthly viewers.
- Collaborated with Samsung, Logitech, MSi, and more to publish over 30 product reviews and editorials.

EDUCATION

University of Windsor

December 2023

Bachelors in Computer Science, Minor in Communications, Media & Film | GPA: 3.9/4.0 | President's List

PROJECTS (MORE ON AFROKK.DEV)

<u>litmus.tools</u> | TypeScript, React, WebAssembly, JavaScript, Vercel | <u>GitHub</u>

January 2023

- A full-stack geographical tax calculator built using TypeScript, WebAssembly, and React in an aesthetic package.
- Integrated data from the **US National Bureau of Economic Research** to provide users with accurate calculations and insights of their savings, earnings, and taxes, all based on their **individual** ZIP codes.

BlazeGuard | TypeScript, React, NextJS 13, Express, Python, mySQL | GitHub

September 2023

- Developed a full-stack web app enabling real-time wildfire monitoring by integrating NASA VIIRS Satellite data and user reports bolstered by AI validation, to enhance early fire detection and promote public awareness.
- Utilized AI for geotagged image analysis, improving rapid wildfire data accuracy by 40%, and showcased active fire trends with a monthly graph. Built using React & TypeScript for frontend and JavaScript & Express for backend.

afrokk.dev | JavaScript, React, NextJS 13, TypeScript, Sanity CMS, SASS | GitHub

May 2023

- My **full-stack** personal developer portfolio built from scratch to showcase my profile and projects.
- Implemented advanced features like SSR, light/dark mode, lazy loading, custom lightbox, carousels, and scroll bars.

Plus <u>CSHub</u>, Car Dealership DBMS, Airport Simulator (Java), OpenQASM: Article, Vintage Autohaus, and <u>more</u>.

EXTRA CURRICULARS

NASA Space Apps 2023: Won 1st place at NASA Space Apps 2023 regional competition in a cohort of over 50 teams.

CS Games 2023: Represented uWindsor in Quebec, implemented cross-platform microservices for security and data sharing.